<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Leonardo Lazzaro</title><link>https://www.lazzaro.com.ar/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Leonardo Lazzaro</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.lazzaro.com.ar/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tutorial on how to setup a node.js application behind nginx</title><link>https://www.lazzaro.com.ar/post/2016-10-14-setup-nodejs-with-nginx/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.lazzaro.com.ar/post/2016-10-14-setup-nodejs-with-nginx/</guid><description>Introduction Node.js is a JavaScript runtime built on Chrome V8 JavaScript engine. Node.js uses an event-driven, non-blocking I/O model that makes it lightweight and efficient. NGINX is a free, open-source, high-performance HTTP server and reverse proxy, as well as an IMAP/POP3 proxy server.
In this brief tutorial we will setup how to configure a small production application that will use nginx as a reverse proxy for serving the node.js application. For managing node.</description></item><item><title>Installing bluehydra on raspberry pi</title><link>https://www.lazzaro.com.ar/post/2016-08-23-bluehydra-raspberrypi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.lazzaro.com.ar/post/2016-08-23-bluehydra-raspberrypi/</guid><description>Introduction ap BlueHydra is a Bluetooth device discovery service built on top of the bluez library. In this tutorial we are going to give the steps to install bluehydra on the rasperberry pi using Raspbian GNU/Linux 8 (jessie). If you are using raspbien wheezy, please see the Apendix
Installing ruby with rvm There are several ways to install ruby, the one I prefer is with rvm. rvm is is a command-line tool which allows you to easily install, manage, and work with multiple ruby environments.</description></item><item><title>Monitor linux statistics with grafana (munin replacement)</title><link>https://www.lazzaro.com.ar/post/2016-08-18-using-grafana-to-monitor-linux-or-to-replace-munin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.lazzaro.com.ar/post/2016-08-18-using-grafana-to-monitor-linux-or-to-replace-munin/</guid><description>This quick tutorial will guide you to install grafana to monitor a linux system. We also are going to save a history to an influx database.
Installing InfluxDB For Ubuntu
curl -sL https://repos.influxdata.com/influxdb.key | sudo apt-key add - source /etc/lsb-release echo &amp;#34;deb https://repos.influxdata.com/${DISTRIB_ID,,}${DISTRIB_CODENAME}stable&amp;#34; | sudo tee /etc/apt/sources.list.d/influxdb.list Install and start theInfluxDB service:
sudo apt-get update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt-get install influxdb sudo service influxdb start Now you can check at the port 8083 (for a local installation check http://localhost:3000)) that the InfluxDB is working.</description></item><item><title>Using JabRef with LibreOffice</title><link>https://www.lazzaro.com.ar/post/2016-06-27-using-jabref-with-libreoffice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.lazzaro.com.ar/post/2016-06-27-using-jabref-with-libreoffice/</guid><description>I Started to use JabRef as a database of BibTex reference for using it with LaTex and LibreOffce. Googling around I found a post that were using a plugin to integrate JabRef with Libreoffice, however it was old and today is not necessary to instal a plugin. Steps to integrate LibreOffice with JabRef
Configure LibreOffice Go to Preferences &amp;gt; LibreOffice &amp;gt; Advanced and make sure that &amp;ldquo;Use a Java runtime environment&amp;rdquo; is checked and that a runtime is properly selected in the installed list.</description></item><item><title>Magic tricks with fold functions</title><link>https://www.lazzaro.com.ar/post/2014-04-18-magic-tricks-with-fold-functions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.lazzaro.com.ar/post/2014-04-18-magic-tricks-with-fold-functions/</guid><description>The first time you deal with foldr seems to be nothing more than a new function like map, filter.
However when you get the concept of recursion scheme, foldr becames a magical function. In most of the cases I used simple explicit recursion calls, like this one:
sum:: Num a =&amp;gt; [a] -&amp;gt; a sum [] = 0 sum (x:xs) = x + (sum xs) Very easy and intuitive to read, but what if we try to compute prod?</description></item><item><title>PYTHON PIL IOERROR DECODER JPEG NOT AVAILABLE</title><link>https://www.lazzaro.com.ar/post/2011-05-07-solved-python-pil-ioerror-decoder-jpeg-not-available/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.lazzaro.com.ar/post/2011-05-07-solved-python-pil-ioerror-decoder-jpeg-not-available/</guid><description>The first thing I check when I got this error was to check if libjpeg was installed.
Lets try this
sudo apt-get install libjpeg libjpeg-dev sudo apt-get install libfreetype6 libfreetype6-dev download jpeg source tar -xzvf jpegsrc.v8c.tar.gz cd jpeg-6b/ ./configure make sudo make install For zlib support (png/zip)
sudo ln -s /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/libz.so /usr/lib So download Python Imaging Library 1.1.7 Source Kit (all platforms)
The after run the setup.py install, check if the support was ok</description></item></channel></rss>